<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pavel Dimens</title><link>https://pdimens.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Pavel Dimens</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 23:29:21 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pdimens.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Structure</title><link>https://pdimens.github.io/posts/structuretutorial/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 23:29:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pdimens.github.io/posts/structuretutorial/</guid><description>Background Structure is a brilliant intellectual work. Structure is also not user-friendly. In fact, one might go so far as to say it&amp;rsquo;s sometimes user-hostile.
User hostility
extremely unforgiving input file parsing manual is not terribly user friendly program is not user friendly GUI version isn&amp;rsquo;t great for long runs (i.e. modern data) two different parameter files there are a million parameters default plots suck and aren&amp;rsquo;t dichromat friendly runs on a single thread/cpu and takes a while depending on your data So, using Structure is largely about navigating these pitfalls.</description></item><item><title>Species Graphics</title><link>https://pdimens.github.io/gallery/species/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 18:35:46 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pdimens.github.io/gallery/species/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Technical Graphics</title><link>https://pdimens.github.io/gallery/technical/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 18:35:46 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pdimens.github.io/gallery/technical/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Snakemake 101</title><link>https://pdimens.github.io/posts/snakemake101/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 23:29:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pdimens.github.io/posts/snakemake101/</guid><description>Install Snakemake To simplify this tutorial, install Snakemake using conda. See the conda tutorial on this site if you need guidance for that process.
Create conda environment with snakemake installation
conda create -n snake_env Activate the environment and install snakemake into it
conda activate snake_env conda install -c bioconda snakemake conda install pydot # will let us see graphs of the workflows Create a new directory for us to play around in</description></item><item><title>Writing clean BASH scripts</title><link>https://pdimens.github.io/posts/bashscripting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 23:29:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pdimens.github.io/posts/bashscripting/</guid><description>While you don&amp;rsquo;t need to know everything about sh or bash to write functional code, you&amp;rsquo;ll find that like R, there are certain ways to write code that end up making life easier for you. This tutorial is meant to share some of those methods so you can have less headaches along the way. By no means is this a &amp;ldquo;you will be awesome at BASH after reading this&amp;rdquo;, but rather a &amp;ldquo;this will make life easier.</description></item><item><title>Powerpoint Mastery</title><link>https://pdimens.github.io/posts/powerpointskills/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 23:29:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pdimens.github.io/posts/powerpointskills/</guid><description>Take your powerpoint slides to the next level
Let&amp;rsquo;s just clear the air and admit most presentations look bad. It&amp;rsquo;s an unfortunate thing, but it&amp;rsquo;s true. Most people who make slide-based presentations (i.e. PowerPoint) aren&amp;rsquo;t skilled at design (I&amp;rsquo;m not), have no formal PowerPoint training (I don&amp;rsquo;t), and only know as much as they need to in order to make presentations (also me). On top of that, often times you&amp;rsquo;re strapped for time and aren&amp;rsquo;t overly concerned with making a knockout presentation so long as it&amp;rsquo;s done (think conferences, lectures).</description></item><item><title>Achieving Good Visuals</title><link>https://pdimens.github.io/posts/goodvisuals/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 23:29:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pdimens.github.io/posts/goodvisuals/</guid><description>At conferences, you either present your work in the form of an oral presentation (powerpoint + speaking) or as a poster. While I cannot enforce what I consider good presentation skills, I can however try to encourage others to improve the visual elements of their presentations. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen lots of good talks and posters marred by awful graphics, maps, organization, wordiness, or a slew of other things that just makes the process of absorbing new material needlessly agonizing.</description></item><item><title>Effective Presentation Skills</title><link>https://pdimens.github.io/posts/effectivepresentations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 23:29:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pdimens.github.io/posts/effectivepresentations/</guid><description>A lot of science happens behind closed doors, in sometimes cold and/or dark spaces. When you do see the light of day and have to communicate your research to the greater community (scientific or otherwise), you should be able to do so effectively.
effectively?
Seems obvious, right? Well, let&amp;rsquo;s first explore what that means. Thinking you do a good or good enough job is great (and I admire the confidence!), but your idea of &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; and your audience&amp;rsquo;s reception of your presentation can be quite different.</description></item><item><title>Graphic Design Tutorial</title><link>https://pdimens.github.io/posts/graphics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 23:29:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pdimens.github.io/posts/graphics/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s make a graphic!
As I&amp;rsquo;m hoping you&amp;rsquo;ve already read, I talk a lot about making your own graphics. Well, to supplement that, I want to include a brief tutorial on how to make the &amp;ldquo;minimal&amp;rdquo; style graphics that I use for my own work. This is done entirely in Inkscape (free and open source!), and working with only my laptop&amp;rsquo;s touchpad and taking all the screenshots, this took me me just about 45min to make.</description></item><item><title>Using Conda in your workflow</title><link>https://pdimens.github.io/posts/conda/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 23:29:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pdimens.github.io/posts/conda/</guid><description>At some point, you may have come across tutorials and posts online referring to conda Anaconda or miniconda and just ignored it (we&amp;rsquo;ve all been there, no judgement). Hopefully by the end of this writing, you will be convinced that conda can be a big deal and make your life quite a bit easier.
Virtual environments Why bother?
If you&amp;rsquo;ve read a tutorial for the command screen and have used it, or run something inside a virtualbox, you may already understand why virtual environments can be great.</description></item></channel></rss>