<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tutorial on Pavel Dimens</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/github.io/tags/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tutorial on Pavel Dimens</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 23:29:21 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/github.io/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Structure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/github.io/posts/structuretutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 23:29:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/github.io/posts/structuretutorial/</guid>
      <description>Background Structure is a brilliant intellectual work. Structure is also not user-friendly. In fact, one might go so far as to say it&amp;rsquo;s sometimes user-hostile.&#xA;User hostility&#xA;extremely unforgiving input file parsing manual is not terribly user friendly program is not user friendly GUI version isn&amp;rsquo;t great for long runs (i.e. modern data) two different parameter files there are a million parameters default plots suck and aren&amp;rsquo;t dichromat friendly runs on a single thread/cpu and takes a while depending on your data So, using Structure is largely about navigating these pitfalls.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Snakemake 101</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/github.io/posts/snakemake101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 23:29:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/github.io/posts/snakemake101/</guid>
      <description>Install Snakemake To simplify this tutorial, install Snakemake using conda. See the conda tutorial on this site if you need guidance for that process.&#xA;Create conda environment with snakemake installation&#xA;conda create -n snake_env Activate the environment and install snakemake into it&#xA;conda activate snake_env conda install -c bioconda snakemake conda install pydot # will let us see graphs of the workflows Create a new directory for us to play around in</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing clean BASH scripts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/github.io/posts/bashscripting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 23:29:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/github.io/posts/bashscripting/</guid>
      <description>While you don&amp;rsquo;t need to know everything about sh or bash to write functional code, you&amp;rsquo;ll find that like R, there are certain ways to write code that end up making life easier for you. This tutorial is meant to share some of those methods so you can have less headaches along the way. By no means is this a &amp;ldquo;you will be awesome at BASH after reading this&amp;rdquo;, but rather a &amp;ldquo;this will make life easier.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphic Design Tutorial</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/github.io/posts/graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 23:29:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/github.io/posts/graphics/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s make a graphic!&#xA;As I&amp;rsquo;m hoping you&amp;rsquo;ve already read, I talk a lot about making your own graphics. Well, to supplement that, I want to include a brief tutorial on how to make the &amp;ldquo;minimal&amp;rdquo; style graphics that I use for my own work. This is done entirely in Inkscape (free and open source!), and working with only my laptop&amp;rsquo;s touchpad and taking all the screenshots, this took me me just about 45min to make.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Conda in your workflow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/github.io/posts/conda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 23:29:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/github.io/posts/conda/</guid>
      <description>At some point, you may have come across tutorials and posts online referring to conda Anaconda or miniconda and just ignored it (we&amp;rsquo;ve all been there, no judgement). Hopefully by the end of this writing, you will be convinced that conda can be a big deal and make your life quite a bit easier.&#xA;Virtual environments Why bother?&#xA;If you&amp;rsquo;ve read a tutorial for the command screen and have used it, or run something inside a virtualbox, you may already understand why virtual environments can be great.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
